flightview.com 2018-12-16

# flightview.com Privacy / Cookie Use

#### Welcome to the OAG privacy notice.

The OAG Aviation Group respects your privacy and is committed to protecting your personal data. This privacy notice aims to give you information on how the OAG Aviation Group collects and processes your personal data gathered through any one of the ways we may engage with you such as (without limitation), when you create an account on the flightview.com website (our website) (regardless of where you visit it from), or you use our mobile flight tracking apps. This privacy notice is provided in a layered format so you can click through to the specific areas set out below. Please also use the Glossary to understand the meaning of some of the terms used in this privacy notice. 

1\. IMPORTANT INFORMATION AND WHO WE ARE

2\. HOW TO CONTACT US

3\. THE DATA WE COLLECT ABOUT YOU

4\. HOW IS YOUR PERSONAL DATA COLLECTED

5\. HOW WE USE YOUR PERSONAL DATA

6\. DISCLOSURES OF YOUR PERSONAL DATA

7\. INTERNATIONAL TRANSFERS

8\. DATA SECURITY

9\. DATA RETENTION

10\. YOUR LEGAL RIGHTS

11\. GLOSSARY

#### 1\. Important information and who we are

It is important that you read this privacy notice together with any other privacy notice or fair processing notice we may provide on specific occasions when we are collecting or processing personal data about you so that you are fully aware of how and why we are using your data. This privacy notice supplements the other notices and is not intended to override them. 

Our website is not intended for children and we do not knowingly collect data relating to children. 

##### Controller

The OAG Aviation Group is made up of different legal entities, details of which are below. This privacy notice is issued on behalf of the OAG Aviation Group, so when we mention the OAG Aviation Group, "we", "us" or "our" in this privacy notice, we are referring to the relevant company in the OAG Aviation Group responsible for processing your data. 

Flightview.com is owned by OAG Aviation Worldwide LLC. 

OAG Aviation Worldwide Limited is the controller where data is collected (i) within the European Economic Area (EEA), Africa, the Middle East; and (ii) in Japan (for print products only). 

OAG Aviation Worldwide LLC is the controller where data is collected in the Americas and the Caribbean. 

OAG Aviation Pte Ltd is the controller where data is collected (i) in all other regions of the world and (ii) in Japan (for digital solutions only). 

Where you reside in the UK you have the right to make a complaint at any time to the Information Commissioner's Office (ICO), the UK supervisory authority for data protection issues (www.ico.org.uk). Where you reside outside the UK but within the EEA you have a right to make a complaint at any time to the appropriate supervisory authority for your country of residence. See http://ec.europa.eu for these details. 

Where you reside outside of the EEA we will apply your legal rights as applicable to the data laws in the jurisdiction you are in. 

We would, however, appreciate the chance to deal with your concerns before you approach the ICO or any other supervisory authority so please contact us in the first instance. 

##### What entities are part of the OAG Aviation Group

  * OAG Aviation Worldwide Limited (UK)
  * OAG Aviation Worldwide LLC (USA)
  * OAG Aviation Worldwide Pte Ltd (Singapore)

#### 2\. How to contact us

We have appointed a group data protection officer (DPO) who is responsible for overseeing questions in relation to this privacy notice. If you have any questions about this privacy notice, including any requests to exercise your legal rights, please contact us using the details set out below: 

Email Address:|    privacy@oag.com  
---|---  
   Postal Address:|    1 Capability Green, Luton, Bedfordshire, LU1 3LU, United Kingdom  
Phone:|    +44 (0)1582 695050  
  
##### Changes to the privacy notice and your duty to inform us of changes

This version was last updated on 2018/05/24. 

It is important that the personal data we hold about you is accurate and current. Please keep us informed if your personal data changes during your relationship with us. 

##### Third-party links

Our website may include links to third-party websites, plug-ins and applications. Clicking on those links or enabling those connections may allow third parties to collect or share data about you. We do not control these third-party websites and are not responsible for their privacy statements. When you leave our websites, we encourage you to read the privacy notice of every website you visit. 

#### 3\. The data we collect about you

Personal data, or personal information, means any information about an individual from which that person can be identified. It does not include data where the identity has been removed (anonymous data). 

We may collect, use, store and transfer different kinds of personal data about you which we have grouped together as follows:

  * Identity Data includes first name, last name, title, username or similar identifier, and airline ticket number.
  * Contact Data includes home address, email address and telephone numbers.
  * Transaction Data includes details of products and services you have purchased from us.
  * Technical Data includes internet protocol (IP) address, your login data, browser type and version, time zone setting and location, language, browser plug-in types and versions, operating system and platform and other technology on the devices you use to access our website and use our mobile apps. 
  * Profile Data includes your username and password, home airport and favourite airline, purchases or orders made by you, your interests, preferences and feedback. 
  * Usage Data includes information about how you use our website, products and services. 

We do not collect any Special Categories of Personal Data about you (this includes details about your race or ethnicity, religious or philosophical beliefs, sex life, sexual orientation, political opinions, trade union membership, information about your health and genetic and biometric data). Nor do we collect any information about criminal convictions and offences. 

##### If you fail to provide personal data

Where we need to collect personal data by law, or under the terms of a contract we have with you and you fail to provide that data when requested, we may not be able to perform the contract we have or are trying to enter into with you (for example, to provide you with goods or services). In this case, we may have to cancel a product or service you have with us but we will notify you if this is the case at the time. 

#### 4\. How is your personal data collected?

We use different methods to collect data from and about you including through: 

**Direct interactions** : You may give us your Identity and Contact Data by filling in forms or by corresponding with us by post, phone, email or otherwise. This includes personal data you provide when you:

  * use our products or services; or
  * create an account on flightview.com (become a user);
  * subscribe to our service or publications; 
  * request marketing (e.g. a newsletter) to be sent to you;
  * make an enquiry via our websites; or
  * give us some feedback. 

**Automated technologies or interactions** : As you interact with our website and use our mobile apps, we may automatically collect Technical Data about your equipment, browsing actions and patterns of use. We collect this personal data by using cookies, server logs and other similar technologies. Please see our cookie notice for further details. 

#### 5\. How we use your personal data

We will only use your personal data when the law allows us to. Most commonly, we will use your personal data in the following circumstances:

  * Where we need to perform the contract we are about to enter into or have entered into with you. 
  * Where it is necessary for our legitimate interests (or those of a third party) and your interests and fundamental rights do not override those interests. 
  * Where we need to comply with a legal or regulatory obligation. 
  * Where you have given your consent. 
  * From time to time we may ask you to voluntarily complete a survey for market research purposes; all data is anonymous and we do not consider this processing personal data. 

See Lawful Basis to find out more about the types of lawful basis that we will rely on to process your personal data. 

##### Purposes for which we will use your personal data

We have set out below, in a table format, a description of all the ways we plan to use your personal data, and which of the legal bases we rely on to do so. We have also identified what our legitimate interests are where appropriate. 

Note that we may process your personal data for more than one lawful ground depending on the specific purpose for which we are using your data. Please contact us if you need details about the specific legal ground we are relying on to process your personal data where more than one ground has been set out in the table below. 

**Purpose/Activity**

| 

**Type of data**

| 

**Lawful basis for processing including basis of legitimate interest**  
  
---|---|---  
  
To register you as a new customer

| 

(a) Identity 

(b) Contact

| 

Performance of a contract with you  
  
To process and deliver your order 

| 

(a) Identity 

(b) Contact 

(c) Transaction 

| 

Performance of a contract with you   
  
To manage our relationship with you which will include:

(a) Notifying you about changes to our terms or privacy notice

| 

(a) Identity 

(b) Contact 

(c) Usage

(d) Profile 

| 

(a) Performance of a contract with you 

(b) Necessary to comply with a legal obligation

(c) Necessary for our legitimate interests (to keep our records updated and to study how customers use our products/services)  
  
To administer and protect our business and our website (including troubleshooting, data analysis, testing, system maintenance, support, reporting and hosting of data) 

| 

(a) Identity

(b) Contact

(c) Technical

| 

(a) Necessary for our legitimate interests (for running our business, provision of administration and IT services, network security, to prevent fraud and in the context of a business reorganisation or group restructuring exercise or sale)

(b) Necessary to comply with a legal obligation  
  
To use data analytics to improve our websites, products/services, customer relationships and experiences

| 

(a) Technical 

(b) Usage 

| 

Necessary for our legitimate interests (to define types of customers for our products and services, to keep our website updated and relevant, and to develop our business)  
  
Targeted third party advertisements to you

| 

Technical 

| 

Consent

OAG does not provide personal data to any advertiser when you interact with or view a targeted ad.  Advertisers (including ad serving companies) may assume that people who interact with, view or click targeted ads meet the targeting criteria. 

If you do not want to see targeted advertisements you may at any time either (i) switch to our paid apps, which do not contain advertising, or (ii) stop using our Flightview free app or website, as the case may be.  
  
##### Third-party marketing

We will get your express opt-in consent before we share your personal data with any company outside the OAG Aviation Group of companies for marketing purposes. 

##### Cookies

You can set your browser to refuse all or some browser cookies, or to alert you when websites set or access cookies. If you disable or refuse cookies, please note that some parts of our website may become inaccessible or not function properly. For more information about the cookies we use, please see our Cookie Notice. To revoke acceptance of cookies you have already granted, you may click here. 

##### Change of purpose

We will only use your personal data for the purposes for which we collected it, unless we reasonably consider that we need to use it for another reason and that reason is compatible with the original purpose. If you wish to get an explanation as to how the processing for the new purpose is compatible with the original purpose, please contact us. 

If we need to use your personal data for an unrelated purpose, we will notify you and we will explain the legal basis which allows us to do so. 

Please note that we may process your personal data without your knowledge or consent, in compliance with the above rules, where this is required or permitted by law. 

#### 6\. Disclosures of your personal data

We may have to share your personal data for the purposes set out in the _How we use your personal data_ table above with the parties listed here:

  * Internal Third Parties as set out in the Glossary.
  * External Third Parties as set out in the Glossary.
  * Third parties to whom we may choose to sell, transfer, or merge parts of our business or our assets. Alternatively, we may seek to acquire other businesses or merge with them. If a change happens to our business, then the new owners may use your personal data in the same way as set out in this privacy notice.

We require all third parties to respect the security of your personal data and to treat it in accordance with the law. We do not allow our third-party service providers to use your personal data for their own purposes and only permit them to process your personal data for specified purposes and in accordance with our instructions. 

#### 7\. International transfers

We share your personal data within the OAG Aviation Group. This will involve transferring your data outside the EEA, as it is a global concern. 

We ensure your personal data is protected by requiring all our group companies located outside the EEA to sign standard contractual clauses determined by the European Commission. 

Many of our External Third Parties are based outside the EEA so their processing of your personal data will involve a transfer of data outside the EEA. 

Whenever we transfer your personal data out of the EEA, we ensure a similar degree of protection is afforded to it by ensuring that the recipient third party agrees to standard contractual clauses determined by the European Commission. 

Please contact us if you want further information on the specific mechanism used by us when transferring your personal data out of the EEA. 

#### 8\. Data security

We have put in place appropriate security measures to prevent your personal data from being accidentally lost, used or accessed in an unauthorised way, altered or disclosed. In addition, we limit access to your personal data to those employees, agents, contractors and other third parties who have a business need to know. They will only process your personal data on our instructions and they are subject to a duty of confidentiality. 

We have put in place procedures to deal with any suspected personal data breach and will notify you and any applicable regulator of a breach where we are legally required to do so. 

#### 9\. Data retention

##### How long will you use my personal data for?

By law we have to keep basic information about our customers (including Contact, Identity and Transaction Data) for certain periods of time, e.g. seven years after they cease being customers for financial, accounting and tax purposes. For our retention policy regarding other areas of the business please contact us for more details. 

In some circumstances you can ask us to delete your data: see [Request erasure] below for further information. 

In some circumstances we may anonymise your personal data (so that it can no longer be associated with you) for research or statistical purposes in which case we may use this information indefinitely without further notice to you. 

#### 10\. Your legal rights

Under certain circumstances, you have rights under data protection laws in relation to your personal data:

  * Request access to your personal data (commonly known as a "data subject access request"). This enables you to receive a copy of the personal data we hold about you and to check that we are lawfully processing it.
  * Request correction of the personal data that we hold about you. This enables you to have any incomplete or inaccurate data we hold about you corrected, though we may need to verify the accuracy of the new data you provide to us.
  * Request erasure of your personal data. This enables you to ask us to delete or remove personal data where there is no good reason for us continuing to process it. You also have the right to ask us to delete or remove your personal data where you have successfully exercised your right to object to processing (see below), where we may have processed your information unlawfully or where we are required to erase your personal data to comply with local law. Note, however, that we may not always be able to comply with your request of erasure for specific legal reasons which will be notified to you, if applicable, at the time of your request.
  * Object to processing of your personal data where we are relying on a legitimate interest (or those of a third party) and there is something about your particular situation which makes you want to object to processing on this ground as you feel it impacts on your fundamental rights and freedoms. You also have the right to object where we are processing your personal data for direct marketing purposes. In some cases, we may demonstrate that we have compelling legitimate grounds to process your information which override your rights and freedoms.
  * Request restriction of processing of your personal data. This enables you to ask us to suspend the processing of your personal data in the following scenarios: (a) if you want us to establish the data's accuracy; (b) where our use of the data is unlawful but you do not want us to erase it; (c) where you need us to hold the data even if we no longer require it as you need it to establish, exercise or defend legal claims; or (d) you have objected to our use of your data but we need to verify whether we have overriding legitimate grounds to use it.
  * Request the transfer of your personal data to you or to a third party. We will provide to you, or a third party you have chosen, your personal data in a structured, commonly used, machine-readable format. Note that this right only applies to automated information which you initially provided consent for us to use or where we used the information to perform a contract with you.
  * Withdraw consent at any time where we are relying on consent to process your personal data. However, this will not affect the lawfulness of any processing carried out before you withdraw your consent. If you withdraw your consent, we may not be able to provide certain products or services to you. We will advise you if this is the case at the time you withdraw your consent.

If you wish to exercise any of the rights set out above, please contact us. 

##### No fee usually required

You will not have to pay a fee to access your personal data (or to exercise any of the other rights). However, we may charge a reasonable fee if your request is clearly unfounded, repetitive or excessive. Alternatively, we may refuse to comply with your request in these circumstances. 

##### What we may need from you

We may need to request specific information from you to help us confirm your identity and ensure your right to access your personal data (or to exercise any of your other rights). This is a security measure to ensure that personal data is not disclosed to any person who has no right to receive it. We may also contact you to ask you for further information in relation to your request to speed up our response. 

##### Time limit to respond

We try to respond to all legitimate requests within one month. Occasionally it may take us longer than a month if your request is particularly complex or you have made a number of requests. In this case, we will notify you and keep you updated. 

#### 11\. Glossary

##### LAWFUL BASIS

Legitimate Interest means the interest of our business in conducting and managing our business to enable us to give you the best service/product and the best and most secure experience. We make sure we consider and balance any potential impact on you (both positive and negative) and your rights before we process your personal data for our legitimate interests. We do not use your personal data for activities where our interests are overridden by the impact on you (unless we have your consent or are otherwise required or permitted to by law). You can obtain further information about how we assess our legitimate interests against any potential impact on you in respect of specific activities by contacting us. 

Performance of Contract means processing your data where it is necessary for the performance of a contract to which you are a party or to take steps at your request before entering into such a contract. 

Comply with a legal or regulatory obligation means processing your personal data where it is necessary for compliance with a legal or regulatory obligation to which we are subject. 

Consent means where you have given your consent. 

##### THIRD PARTIES

**Internal Third Parties** : Other companies in the OAG Aviation Group [link to section called What entities are part of the OAG Aviation Group]. 

**External Third Parties** :

  * Service providers acting as processors based either within the EEA or outside of the EEA (and so are subject to specific contractual requirements) who provide IT and system administration services.
  * Professional advisers including lawyers, bankers, auditors and insurers based within the EEA or outside of the EEA, who provide consultancy, banking, legal, insurance and accounting services.
  * HM Revenue & Customs, regulators and other authorities based within the EEA or outside of the EEA who require reporting of processing activities in certain circumstances.
